本视频由KurtzPel以及KOG游戏赞助
this video is sponsored by KurtzPel and kog games
是个免费动漫风的角色扮演RPG端游
KurtzPel is a free-to-play anime style action RPG for PC KurtzPel
你可以在以下的链接下载
that is available in the link below
首先我要说的是这游戏的连击战斗系统是我玩过的最好的动漫风格的MMO游戏了
right off the bat I’ve got to say that this game honestly is one of the most satisfying action combat systems I’ve played in an anime MMO game
打击感很好，连招做的也很华丽
attacks feel good and weighty chaining combos with special moves that's cool as hell
战斗也十分具有挑战性
and overall battles can actually be quite challenging
别忘了这看起来都十分精美
not forgetting that it all looks absolutely beautiful
从各种不同的职业中选择适合你的
choose from a variety of different classes
发挥创造出自己的风格
to suit your play style
选择你想要成为的角色
and also create your own character to suit whatever a protagonist you want to be
你可以成为一个龙傲天主角
you can be an Opie anime guy
或者老实说吧我们可以成为一个妹子
or let's be honest we're gonna be a girl
因为在现实生活中我们不可能去角色扮演一个动画风的萌妹子的
cuz when in life wouldn't I choose to roleplay as a cute anime girl
你可以去自定义你的所有外貌
see you can edit all the important features like
眼睛颜色，发型，还有
eye color hair style and
啊～～～～
yeah
目前，这游戏正在北美和拉丁美洲提前测试中
currently the game was in early access for North and Latin America
PvP无论你是想玩PVE还是想在PVP中被虐
where you can play either PvE or get your ass handed to you in
我也对开发商倾听玩家声音和及时反馈的态度印象深刻
I've been impressed at how closely the developers are listening to feedback
很快的定位解决玩家在游戏中遇到的问题
quickly addressing any issues the player base may have had with the game
如果你想体验这游戏的话
if you want to try it out again
点击以下链接在Steam上下载吧
click the link in the description to give it a download on Steam
说完广告，让我们进入今天的视频
and with that said let's get on with the video
这儿有个我认为已经在动画社区里逝去的概念
there's a concept I feel has died as of late within our community
那个曾经是我们动画社区标准的一份子
one that used to be a standard part of getting into the medium
那就是经典动画
and that is the idea around classic anime
经典动画开创了我们看到的这些系列动画的先河
animes that defines their generation and pioneered the landscape you see today
在之前，回过头去看几部经典动画基本上是所有人都会去做的
it used to be mandatory to at least go back and watch a handful of them
但现如今，似乎没有必要再去看看经典动画来让自己变得更婆
but nowadays not only is there less obligation to get yourself cultured by watching these shows
我也觉得无论现在的新番有多么棒
I also kind of feel like no matter how great any new anime coming out is
它们身上也没有那种我会把它们称作“经典新番”这样的东西
there's nothing that really sticks tells me that we could call a modern classic
我在我的「2018年最佳动画」的那个视频里提到过
I’ve already handedly mentioned in my best of anime 2018 video
无论2018年的动画质量是多么的高，其中也没有一部可以称得上是经典的
that despite how great I thought last year was it had zero classics
而我认为更贴切的表述是
which is more my way of describing that
无论那些新番的质量看上去有多么的高
no matter how good any show was
它们身上好像缺了那么些影响力和传世的魅力
it seemed like a sense of impact and longevity
而那是很多伟大的动画年所具有的
that a lot of greater years of anime had
但这引发了一系列的关于“经典究竟是什么的一系列辩论”
but it certainly sparked an unintentional debate in the comments section about what exactly a classic even is
以及我们就下定结论是不是太早了
and whether it's too early to judge
所以今天，我想真正深入探讨下这个话题
so today I wanted to really dig in on that exact topic
现在的新番缺少的究竟是什么，以及为什么经典动画如此重要
what's lacking today and really remind everyone why they were important
我想在这视频里说很多东西，所以废话少说
in the first place there's a lot of different things I want to unpack in this video
让我们直接开始吧
so without further ado let’s just jump into it
什么造就了经典
what makes a classic
不需要废话的是，关于经典的定义是非常主观和因人而异的
I don't think I need to state that the exact parameters of what defines a classic is entirely subjective and probably different for every person
但我还是再次多说了一句废话
but I guess I just did anyway
经典这个词最常见的定义和更广泛的感觉上
most common definitions of the word and a broader sense
是被普遍认可的质量和经得起时间考验的价值
simply played out to be something of universally recognized quality and established ongoing value
然而，对于经典的争论，我总结为三个要点
however for the sake of the arguments I'm making for me it boils down to three main points
首先：后劲
number one staying power
经典之所以是经典是因为无论其经过多少时间的考验
classics are classics because they have stood the test of time
无论多少年过去，它们仍然有着自己的独特魅力
no matter how many years past they will still be relevant in their own way
很多的老动画艺术风格和其作画可能已经有些过时了
there are many older anime that have aged in some way mainly to do with their art style or animation有
但它们却保留了一种永恒的感觉
but have preserved a sense of timelessness
它们的故事和人物在任何时代都能够去享受
with either their story or characters that can be enjoyed in any era
顺便一提，有很多动画具有其独特的开创性意义，开创了很多传奇的故事
as a side note that have been many shows that set trends and pioneered legendary tropes
它们在它们诞生的那个年代无疑是前卫新颖和标志性的
on the bleeding edge of war was fresh and significant in a time they came out
但随着这些元素在后世变得俗套，它们逐渐失去了它们身上的光芒
but have lost a lot of their luster through these elements becoming oversaturated years later
举个例子「圣天空战记」，开创了许多元素，过去有一段时间内它被奉为经典
the vision of escaflowne for example pioneered a lot of things and there was a time it was considered a classic
而我相信即使是现在很多人也这样想
and I'm sure many still do now
对新观众安利这部动画比较困难
though it's a lot harder to recommend for newer audiences
很多新观众可能就把看作一部普通的异世界机站动画
as most people who watch it for the first time could see it as some generic ISA KY mecha show
因为这些年有太多类型的动画了
because of how overplayed many of its tropes have become since
在我看来，无论一部动画是多么的具有革命性
and in my opinion no matter how revolutionary a show is
它首先要经历的考验就是这个
this is a test it has to overcome
而这就引出了我的下个话题，影响力
which brings me to point number two impact
我认为对于影响力这一点，我们必须要有一个影响程度层次的划分
I feel there needs to be a level of impact and influence
因为从逻辑上来说，动画肯定或多或少在它们播出的年份产生影响
because logically you must have been able to impact in its own time in order for it to be remembered
而这有两种方式
and this goes in two ways
其一是对动画业界产生影响
an impact on the anime industry itself
影响业界之后创作的的动画
that influences future titles and the landscape of anime
其二是影响动画观众和社区流行的文化
or an impact on anime pop culture and the general audience of the time
我想「EVA」或者「阿基拉」这样动画的影响力无需多言
I don't think I need to clarify what kind of impact anime like Neon Genesis Evangelion or Akira hats
但我可以来谈谈最近的一些动画社区产生影响的动画
but I could talk about more recent anime that had a profound impact on anime pop culture
而这是超越了超级赛亚人的超级赛亚人
if I shouted the phrase and this is to go even further beyond
你们以为我是谁啊！
or just who the hell do you think I am
你们有多少人能立刻反应过来我在说什么
how many of you would immediately know what I'm talking about
我认为有些经典动画影响了动画业界
some classics I feel only has an impact
有些经典动画影响了动漫社区的流行文化
on the industry some on pop culture
而有些动画两者兼有
some doing both
我认为动画的影响力如此重要的原因是，如果一个动画什么都好
but I think it’s important because if an anime hits every
但它就是冷门或者影响力不大
other category but isn't that popular or widely influncial
那我就更愿意将其称为“小众经典
（cult classic）when sure my opinion is closer to a cult”
而最后的要素是：质量
and finally number three quality
经典作的背后要不是有着实的质量 就是备受大量好评
The term classic surely implies that there would be a certain level of quality or critical acclaim behind it.
这点和入宅作差不多 入宅作大多都经得起时间考验且又有很大的影响力
You can have something that’s remained relevant for years and is also widely influential as you would see with a lot of gateway anime,
但是除非观众能都达成一致觉得某部作品的水准足够高
but unless there’s a general agreed consensus that it’s up to a certain level of high standards,
没有人会怎么关心的
people won’t take it seriously.
我觉得「刀剑神域」系列就属于这种作品的典范 虽然它在现在比其它同年作品还要有讨论热度
I think the best example of this is the Sword Art Online franchise, which is still way more relevant than arguably any other anime that came out in the same year,
庞大的粉丝群体来支撑 甚至还改变了现代日漫的发展方向
and undoubtably has had the popularity to back it up while influencing the landscape of modern anime,
但是 真的会有人称「刀剑神域」系列为经典吗？
but, would anyone actually call this a classic?
若是考虑到以上全部三点
Now, with these points in mind,
今时今日 如果有的话 有多少动画还能背负得起「经典」这个名号呢？
how many, if any, could you apply all three criteria to an anime today?
「现代经典」都去哪儿了？
WHERE’S THE MODERN CLASSICS
对我来说 我觉得原因主要还是在于现代动漫缺少的那种 经典氛围
To me, it’s the feeling of a modern classic that’s been missing from anime recently,
当然 言下之意绝对不是指动漫正在日渐衰弱
and I don’t want you to get the impression that that means anime has gotten worse.
正相反 动漫每日都在超越昨天的自己 而这就是原因的根本
Quite the opposite in fact, I think it’s better than it’s ever been, and that might actually be it.
每一季度都毫无中断地播放种类如此广泛的高质量动漫
Never before, such a wide variety of high-quality anime being available to us in a constant drip feed of seasonal content,
never giving us a moment’s rest. x
在这番剧质量稍有欠缺的春季中 大量的选择摆在我们面前反而会显得有些刺眼
We’ve been spoiled for choice, and it kind of shows when I think this Spring season is kind of weak
毕竟 能够让我兴奋期待起来的番这季度目前仅仅只有两部
just because it only has two shows I’m super hyped shows,
卡罗尔与星期二
Carole & Tuesday
Attack on Titan Season 3 Part 2
进击的巨人 第三季 第二期
而让我觉得挺好的番剧目前只有五部
and five shows I think are pretty good
Isekai Quartet 异世界四重奏
Sarazanmai 皿三昧
Demon Slayer 鬼灭之刃
Fruits Basket (2019) 水果篮子 重制版
One Punch Man Season 2 一击男 第二季
给 给我滚出去
Get, get, get out of here
你特么的真以为老子没花费生命中的每一滴时间来看
What do you mean I’m not literally spending every free moment
上两季度那些还算值得一看的番啊哈？
trying to keep up with shows worth watching like the last two seasons
卧 槽
Oh, god,
你个番剧季度之耻 不滚出去在这儿瞎摆什么弄
What a, what a fucking failure of a season!
动漫这个媒体也算挺历史久远的了
While there are less shows pioneering new things,
开创新道路新领域的领头番虽然们变少了
which is understandable considering how old this medium is right now,
但是我觉得动漫的平均质量 和供我们选择的番剧数量 无疑都有大量的提升
I think the average quality and very certainly the quantity of choice has gone up.
但是 请别忘记：
But, that’s the thing:
若每个人都器宇不凡 则人人都是凡桃俗李
if everything’s special, nothing is.
三个条件里面 貌似缺少的往往都是后劲 时间的考验
Of all the 3 criteria, it’s staying power that seems to be missing most of the time.
大热和流行的作品和趋势占了御宅社区大多数的话题
Current trends and hype series cover the majority of what remains relevant and impactful throughout the wider community
加上一层又一层的新番盖在话题的中央
with the sheer density of new series being fed to us every season,
就连千载难逢的神作也会被人们速速淡忘
it can become easy to forget even great shows.
曾几何时 我们曾抱怨动漫剧情划水拖沓
We used to complain that anime used to have filler seasons;
数年后的现在 仿佛番剧本身 也变成了划水的存在
now, it feels like we have filler anime.
现在来说新番有没有留在动漫历史的潜力 未必太早
You could argue that it’s far too early to determine which recently aired anime has staying power, but, 有人可能说
但是我觉得 其实就连能撑过三个月的动漫都不多
I’d argue that you’d be hard pressed to find any show that lingers around for longer than 3 months,
更何况几年 甚至数十年的时光
let alone, years or decades later.
新番播出的时间虽不算长 但大概扫个一两眼后 你估计也分析得出哪些番有足够的后劲
Just because not a lot of time has passed doesn’t mean you can’t have a good idea of what will stick round,
在发生后 就马上被赋予「经典」知名的体育赛事可谓数不胜数
There have been plenty of sporting events that have been labelled an instant classic.
「绝命毒师」的最后一集一播出 我就估计到了这一集注定会在电视剧史上画上浓重的一笔
As soon as the last episode of Breaking Bad aired, I knew it was gonna go down in television history;
「无限战争」和「终局之战」早已渗透了流行文化的每一个角落
and with what Infinity War and Endgame have achieved and how much it’s permeated into general pop culture,
无可置疑 它们注定会成为这一代人对「经典」一词的标准答案
I have no doubt they will become classics that have defined this generation.
但是偶尔
On a rare occurrence though,
即使在这样的行风下 我还是会去在成堆的动漫里 挖出一些能够长时间留在我脑海里的奇特玩意儿
I will watch an anime that does something special that would stay in my mind for a very long time, even in this climate.
那种超越常规常识的模板 那些带着神秘X因素的精华 那种能够和神作抗衡的存在
Something that goes above and beyond, even compared to the best, and has that special X factor you rarely see.
我觉得 在最近播出的番剧里最接近「经典」的动漫 就只有「路人超能100 二期」
The anime that I would say has come closest to becoming a classic recently, is Mob Psycho 100 Season 2.
虽然大众估计都会说 它已经是个现代经典了 当然我也了解他们想法的出发点
Hell, I know many of you would probably argue it already is, and I completely get that.
「路人超能100 二期」毫无悬念地是我近年看过最精彩的动漫之一
Season 2 of Mob Psycho is one of the best anime series I’ve seen in years,
甚至远超其第一期所达到的水准
that completely blew the first season out of the water.
它拿着第一期的高潮式作画和上十年间最精彩的打斗场景且再次进行了升华
It somehow levelled up its orgasmic animation with some of the best fight scenes of the last decade,
它有那曾还不算普遍的 耿直却又用心的角色塑造
and paired this with a heart and intimate character writing that wasn’t as prevalent before,
加上无数条串连起来的 完美回收的伏笔们 令「路人超能100 二期」在我脑海里挥之不去
while ending every major plot thread it had set up resulting in an all-around package that will certainly stick with me for years to come.
这部从几乎各方面都完美无瑕的艺术品
It was just such a perfect storm of greatness on every level that you rarely get to see.
究竟还缺了些什么呢
So, what exactly is it missing?
其实 原因就是它标题里的「二期」
Well, it's precisely because, it’s a season two.
不论我怎么下海口夸这部番
As much of a masterpiece as I think it was,
我还是劝不回来一些 在看完一期就弃番的人
a lot of people dropped off after season one,
在这充斥着快餐式动画的行业 加上一期和二期中间整整两年的缺口
which is to be expected in the fast-paced anime cycle,
这似乎也不是什么值得惊讶的事情
and an over two-year gap between seasons.
毕竟就连我都不怎么记得起一期的所有内容
Even I had trouble remembering everything the first season left off at,
这些小事情 可谓是抹杀了「路人超能100 二期」所可能带来的业界冲击
and I’m sure this killed off a lot of the potential wide scale impact it could’ve had.
我敢说 只要把两期动画结合为一期 或者把两期中间的空窗期稍微整短点
I have no doubts that if it was one long season or even if the gap was shorter,
这部番所带来的影响就肯定不会止于此步了
it would’ve permeated the community much deeper than it did.
但其实无论质量如何 它仍然不是季度里最受欢迎的那部番
But as it stands, it wasn’t even the most popular show of its own season.
剧情党平日都在「盾之勇者成名录」旁逗留
There was more discussion around Shield Hero,
所有人都喜欢把期待留给「约定的梦幻岛」这样的大牌新鲜番剧
more fresh hype around Promised Neverlands,
舞蹈区 鬼畜区和玩梗人士则都跳进了「辉夜大小姐想让我告白」那坑里
and more memes around Kaguya-sama.
完美地说明了为什么现在的好番剧往往不会长寿
This I think, perfectly illustrates why it’s so hard for anime today to get a sense of longevity.
现在的动漫早已没有了以前的单一性 因此而失去了曾经所拥有的影响力
Right now, anime has become too segmented to have the same influence,
而御宅社区现在怜新厌旧的本性早已和以前大不相同
and the community moves too fast to have the same staying power it used to.
制造现代经典并非不可能 但绝非易事
I’m sure it’s still possible, it’s just much harder.
现代经典需要有能够在众多同期季番中间脱颖而出的资质
It has to be able to stand up from the dozens of anime it competes with every season,
现代经典需要足够的银幕时间
it has to be given a long enough run time,
需要有影响业界或社区的能力 如果是分期放送则还不可以有长期的缺口
to have a lasting impact without big breaks if it’s broken up into seasons,
现代经典需在有大量用户的视频平台上放送来积攒人气
it has to be easily accessible on a streaming platform that the community will collectively access,
而且不仅如此 现代经典还要
and on top of that, it has to be,
呃 需要
you know,
吊炸天
really fucking good.
但是 虽然说了这么多 我还是想标出一个小小的例外vI do, however, think there’s a small asterisk to this point.
正如我认为每个年代都会有一个定义本年代并沉淀下来成为经典的长篇动画
as i think every generation will have a long-running show in that defines that era and goes down as a classic.
随着他们成为入门动画的主力
[with] they being a staple of gateway anime .
并且这个长篇动画的特点能让它们通过更多的时间去积攒人气、产生影响并维持霸权
and this long-running nature allows it far more time to build the popularity and impact and staying power.
因为好吧它们太持久了
cuz well it sticks around for so long.
那么如果我说的东西外有一个例外呢
so if there is an exception to everything i've said here.
那当然就是「我的英雄学院」啦
it would of course be my hero acadamia，
我由衷地认为这是一部已经实现能被长远地记住的动画
i do think this is the one show that has done enough to be remembered for a long time to come。
但是我也认为这种动画的类型对比于动画世界中的「灵能百分百」有更为不同的准则
but i also consider these types of shows to play by a different set of rules than the mob psychos of the anime world。
因为有认为经典的想法已死的部分原因是
because part of the reason the idea of classics has died is because well
我们并没有回顾过去的迫切需求
we don't fell the need to look back into the past
即使这个过去仅仅只有一两年
even if the past is just a year or two ago
我们有太多的选择了
there's so much to choose from now
为什么还要回顾过去呢
what's the point of looking back
这也是我想做这个视频的真正原因
and thus the real reason i wanted to make this video
因为在过去的几个月内
because over the past few month
我花了很多时间去看那些我以前从来没有看过的经典动画
i actually did set a bit of time to watch some classic anime i had never seen before
这也提醒了我经典为何被称为经典
and it just reminded me why classics are indeed called classics
两个月前我开始了一项艰苦的任务：开始看那些躺在我愿望单好多年的动画
two months ago i set off on an arduous mission to start the anime that had been sitting on my watch list for years
那些等着我做足准备尝试去看的动画
waiting until i was ready to take that leap of faith to finally watch it
「银河英雄传说」
Legend of th Galactic Heroes
它是一个重大的项目， 就和其先于它的名声一样生畏
it was an undertaking that was as intimidating as the reputation that preceded it
其是一个被盛赞的经典，字面意义上的被很多人[模因到死]，包括我
a classic so highly spoken of is literally been memed to death by many people myself included
他作为一个动画被放到了最高的基准上
as the one show that's been put up on the highest pedestal
他们说一旦你看了「银河英雄传说」，动画就和以前不同了
anime won't be the same once you watch Legends of the Galactic Heroes they said
脑中带着这些看法
and with this all in mind
最后我也恰好看到了我期待的东西
what i found was exactly what i had expected
动画史上最伟大的故事之一
one of the greatest stories to have been told in the history of anime
一个壮丽到没有任何其他动画能在广度深度和质量[密度]上与之相比的故事
a tale so grand no other anime even comes close to the scale depth and density of the saga told here
一个花费了10年，有着庞大的110集的独一无二体验的产物
a production that took almost ten years to complete contained in a whopping 110 episodes for a one-of-a-kind experience
在动画这形式中你不可能再找到第二个
you can't find anywhere else in the medium
这不是那种现今寻常的快节奏的包爽动画
it's not the kind of fast-paced instant gratification anime more common today
而是一个你能够慢慢沉浸其中的完整史诗
but a full-length epic you gradually immerse yourself into
看了这个动画你会被深深地沉浸其中
with a show like this you can get so caught up in this reputation
以至于很容易就会忘记如何和为何一开始会得到它的这个赞誉
that it can be easy to forget how and why you've got its reputation in the first place
通过这个提醒了我为何这里曾有那个概念：你需要出去看经典
through this it reminded me why there used to be this big notion that you should go out and watch the classics
并非仅仅因为它很伟大
not just because it was a great show
现如今有很多伟大的动画
there are plenty of great shows that coming out right now
更是因为这是一段独特的体验，一段如今无法复制的体验
but because it's a unique experience from anything you can find today
这就是为何经典不随时间流逝
there's reason the classics have survived the passage of time
他们也许开拓了什么领域
they might have pioneered something
他们也许给那时的观众留下了深刻的印象
they might have left a deep impression on the audience of their time
但最重要的是因为经过他们后面这些年
but most importantly it's because throughout the years that came after
没有新作能够取代他们
nothing came along that was able to replace them
我能自信地说自从我第一次看「星际牛仔」之后
i can safely say since i first watched Cowboy Bebop
没有任何其他动画和其相似
there hasn't been any other show quite like it
「玲音」有对技术的描写
serial experiments lain has a depiction of technology
这描写看起来甚至比1998年的时候看起来更有价值
that somehow seems more relevant today than when it came out in 1998
「阿基拉」的观感仍旧比现在9成的新出动画更好
akira still looks better than 90% of the anime coming out now
「新世纪福音战士」重新定义了什么是典型定义
Neon Genesis Evangelion redefined what it means to be [genre-defining]
很容易就能忘掉现今异世界力量幻想高中XXX的泛滥
it can be easy to forget through the currency of Isekai power fantasy highschool [XXX] of today
看到动画并非一直如此
that anime didn't always look like this
那么如果你认为这季的动画节奏不够明快，而且你还想消磨时间的话
so if you think this season is little slow and you[yet] have some time to fill
只需捡起那些经典正在你愿望单里的吃灰的经典动画吧just pick a classic title that's been collecting dust on your watch list
我保证这是一个更让人满足的体验，比起又看一部过去一年中放送的厕纸动画而言
and i guarantee it'll be a way more fulfilling experience than watching another disposable show that's been airing in the last year
无论你是同意哪些动画构成经典
whether or not you agree on which anime consist classics
或者即使你不同意我说最近没有经典动画的意见
or even if you disagree with my opinion that we haven't gotten any recently
我觉得保持经典存续的想法很重要
i think it's important to keep the idea of classics alive
因为确实感觉最近寿命的价值和回顾过去有所降低
because it does feel like lately there's been a depreciation in the value of longevity and revisiting the past
所以如果这部视频里有我想做的什么事情
so if there's anything i wanted to do with this video
就是提醒人们仍有回顾过去的价值
it's reminding people that there is a reason to look back
在现今的气氛下休息一下，看一看其他时间的作品
it's taking a break from the current climate and having a look at product of another time
就会有这种认识
it's having that realization of
这就是当年每个人都在谈论的东西
oh this is what everyone was talking about
这是在体验一个已经做到了一些值得被记住的成就的作品
it's experiencing a show that has done something to deserve to be remembered
因为我认为对于这些经典来说最悲哀的事情之一莫过于遗忘
because one of the saddest things i think it happened to classics is for them to be forgotten
嗨伙计们 希望你们喜欢这次的视频
hey guys hope you enjoyed that video
再一次我感谢来自KurtzPel和开发商
KOG Games的发电again i want to thank KurtzPel and KOG Games for sponsoring this video
如果你喜欢还想试试的话
if you liked what i showed and want to give it a go
点击下面的链接下载吧
then just click on the link below to download it
同时也感谢以下同学
also thank you very much to
Bddinyolife
Robert Hamilton
Walt-O
SupremeSayain
Nicholas Tatum
和来自我patreon的discord的Michael
Michael from my patreon discord
允许我在这个视频里使用他的一个[]
let me use one of his lines in this video
there Michael
这里Michael
[] 这儿你的尽情地[]
there your free
以及所有在patreon上这个月支持我并让这个视频成为现实的人
and everyone else on my patreon for helping to support me for this month and making this video possible
没怎么更新
not many updates today
这个视频放出来的时候我可能在美国或者冰岛
by the time this video comes out probably be in America or Ireland
旅行
just traveling around
我就先到此为止
so yeah i'll just leave it at that
我是
gigguki've been gigguk
我们下次再见
and i'll see you next time